International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America, Local 67 and Local 144 Records, 1946-1981 AIS.1986.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America, Local 67 and Local 144 Records
1946-1981
ULS Archives & Special Collections
International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Joint Local Executive Board for Locals 22, 67, and 144 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 144 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 67 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1986.06
10 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Workers at western Pennsylvania beer breweries were represented by three locals of the International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 22 represented the brewers, Local 67 represented the drivers, and Local 144 represented the bottlers. This collection includes the records of Locals 67 and 144 at various breweries in western Pennsylvania, as well as records of the Joint Local Executive Board.
Previous Citation
International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America, Locals 67 and 144 Records, 1946-1981, AIS.1986.06, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Pittsburgh Beer Bottlers Local 144 Executive Board in June 1986.
History
Workers at western Pennsylvania beer breweries were represented by three locals of the International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 22 represented the brewers, Local 67 represented the drivers, and Local 144 represented the bottlers. In 1946, Local 144 engaged in a literal battle with a faction of bottlers who formed Teamsters Local 232. The two groups exchanged beatings and fire bombs during the jurisdictional dispute after the breweries refused to recognize the Teamsters and fired anyone who did not return to work, resulting in pickets from the American Federation of Labor. Both Local 144 and 22 are now affiliated with the International Union of Electricians-Communication Workers of America (IUE-CWA).
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes minutes, dues records, and correspondence from International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America Locals 67 and 144. Also included are contracts and financial records from the Joint Local Executive Board, which represented these locals and Local 22.
Separated Material
Oversize materials are located in Range 1/12/3.
Saint Marys (Elk County, Pa.); McKeesport (Pa.); Sharpsburg (Pa.); Smithton (Pa.); Latrobe (Pa.); Beer industry -- Pennsylvania -- McKeesport; Beer industry -- Pennsylvania -- Smithton; Beer industry -- Pennsylvania -- Latrobe; Beer industry -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Brewery workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Latrobe; Brewery workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Saint Marys (Elk County); Brewery workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- McKeesport; Brewery workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Smithton; Brewery workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Sharpsburg; Brewery workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Brewing industry -- Pennsylvania -- Saint Marys (Elk County); Brewing industry -- Pennsylvania -- Latrobe; Brewing industry -- Pennsylvania -- McKeesport; Brewing industry -- Pennsylvania -- Smithton; Brewing industry -- Pennsylvania -- Sharpsburg; Beer industry -- Pennsylvania -- Saint Marys (Elk County); Beer industry -- Pennsylvania -- Sharpsburg; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Brewing industry -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor; International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Joint Local Executive Board for Locals 22, 67, and 144 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Duquesne Brewing Company; Fort Pitt Brewing Company; Iron City Brewing Company; Jones Brewing Company (Smithton, Pa.); Latrobe Brewing Company; Pittsburgh Brewing Company; Straub Brewery; Tube City Brewing Company; International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 144 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America. Local 67 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America, Local 67, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series includes minutes, dues records, membership lists, arbitrations, government filings, contract proposals, and financial accounts of Local 67, which represented drivers, helpers, yardmen and members of the shipping department at: Duquesne Brewing Co. and Iron City Brewing Co. in Pittsburgh; Jones Brewing Co. in Smithton; and Latrobe Brewing Co. in Latrobe.
  - Meeting Minutes, 1942-1943, 1946-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1-25)
  - Dues Records, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 26-43)
  - Arbitration, 1937, 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 44-48)
  - Contracts and Proposals, 1961, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from the International Union (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Joint Local Executive Board (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Local Materials (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Receipts and Notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dues Receipts, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6-10)
  - Membership Lists, 1958, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11-21)
  - Financial Records (Box 2, Folder 22-25)
- International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America, Local 144, II.
  This series includes minutes; dues, membership and financial records; contracts and contract proposals; correspondence; photographs; and charters of Local 144 which represented beer bottlers at: Duquesne Brewing Co., Pittsburgh Brewing Co. and Iron City Brewing Co. in Pittsburgh; Fort Pitt Brewing in Sharpsburg; Jones Brewing Co. in Smithton; Latrobe Brewing Co. in Latrobe; Straub Brewing Co. in St. Mary's; and Tube City Brewing Co. in McKeesport.
  - Dues Records, Duquesne Brewing Co., 1955-1957, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
  - Dues Records, Fort Pitt Brewing Co., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dues Records, Iron City Brewing Co., 1955-1957, 1968-1971, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Dues Records, Jones Brewing Co., 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dues Records, Latrobe Brewing Co., 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dues Records, Pittsburgh Brewing Co., 1956-1957, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 13-20)
  - Dues Records, Straub Brewery, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dues Records, Tube City Brewing Co., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dues Records, Pittsburgh Brewing Co., 1945-1970 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Dues Records, Duquesne Brewing Co., 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
  - Finance Reports, July 1950-April 1969 (Box 3, Volume 1-5)
  - Jones Brewing Dues Receipts, 1956-1957, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Check Books, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Volume 1-4)
  - Expense Receipts and Signatures, 1965-1967, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Expense Books, 1946-1970 (Box 4, Volume 5-9)
  - Payroll Book, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Volume 10)
  - Floral Reports, 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1946-1969 (Box 5, Volume 1-6)
  - Audits, 1965, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
  - Audits, 1966-1968, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1-9)
  - Lay-Off Call Books, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Attendence, 1956-1963 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Bottlers Local 144 By-Laws and Photograph (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Membership Books, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Membership Books, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Membership Records, 1955-1964 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
  - Contracts, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 5-9)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1981 (Box 7, Folder 10-14)
  - Miscellaneous Iron City Brewing Co. Records (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Pittsburgh Brewing Co. Records (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Duquesne Brewing Co. Records (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Local 144 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 4)
- International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers of America, Joint Local Executive Board for Locals 22, 67 and 144, III.
  This series contains contracts, contract proposals and financial records of the Joint Local Executive Board which represented the workers of Locals 22, 67 and 144.
  - Agreement with Duquesne Brewing Company, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Volume 1)
  - Agreement with Latrobe Brewing Company, 1972, 1980 (Box 8, Volume 2-3)
  - Agreement with Pittsburgh Brewing Company, 1966, 1972, 1976, 1979 (Box 8, Volume 4-7)
  - Audit, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Financial Spreadsheet, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Working Hours and Wages, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Contract Proposals (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Memorandum of Agreement with Duquesne Brewing Company, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Financial Reports (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Oversize Materials, IV.
  This material was added to the finding aid in January 2011.
  - Certificate of Affiliation of the AFL with the International Union of the United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers, Local 144, 1960; 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 11)
  - Certificate: 50th Anniversary of the Beer Bottlers Union Local 144, 2.
  - Charter: From the AFL to the International Union of United Brewery & Soft Drink Workers, Local 144, 1917; 3.
  - Charter: From the AFL to the International Union of United Brewery & Soft Drink Workers, Local 144, 1956; 4.
  - Charter: From the AFL to the International Union of United Brewery & Soft Drink Workers, Joint Locals 144, 22 and 67, 1934; 5.
  - Photo: 23rd Convention of the International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, and Soft Drink Workers of America, 1923; 6.
  - Membership Ledgers (Oversize 1-4)
  - AFL-CIO Charter, 1973 (Oversize 5)
  - United Brewery Charter, 1969 (Oversize 6)